Quiet.
別出聲
Open the door, open the door.
打開門
What?
什麼？
What in the devil?
到底怎麼回事？
Can you please stand up and take us to the cash drawer, ma'am?
你能站起來 帶我們到現金抽屜那裡麼？
I will not.
我可不會
We ain't asking.
我們不是在問你
There's no money in the drawers yet.
現在抽屜裡還沒有錢
It's in the safe and i ain't got the code.
在保險櫃裡 我沒有密碼
Prove it. Drawer!
看一下 抽屜
Here.
這裡
Open the drawer.
打開抽屜
- I need the keys.- Keys.
- 我需要鑰匙 - 鑰匙
Step back.
靠後
Shit. Damn it!
該死
Y'all are new at this, I'm guessing.
你們是新手 我猜的
Where's the money?
錢在哪裡？
I told you, it's in the safe.
我說過錢在保險櫃裡
Well, who has the code?
好吧 誰有密碼
Mr. clauson.
克勞森先生
He'll be here soon and I suggest you fellas don't be.
他快來了 我勸你們停手吧
All you're guilty of right now is being stupid.
目前為止 你們的罪行頂多是太蠢
Just leave and that's all it'll be.
現在就離開 什麼事都沒有
Tell me I'm stupid again.
再說一次我蠢？
What time does Mr. clauson get here? Ma'am, look at me.
克勞森先生啥時候來？看著我！夫人
What time does Mr. clauson get here, huh?
克勞森先生什麼時候來這裡？
8:30 every morning.
每天早上八點半
We're walking.
走起來
And sit.
坐下
Where do you think you're going?
你覺得你能去哪裡？
Sit on the floor!
坐在地上
You're stupid.
你才蠢呢
This ain't about you, darling.
這不關你事 親愛的
Elsie, you all right?
Elsie 你還好嗎？
Good morning.
早上好
You didn't have to hit him.
你不必揍他
- Slow down.- I ain't speeding.
- 慢點 -我沒有超速。
See, little brother, not a worry in the world.
看 小兄弟 無憂世界
Planning this and doing it is two different things.
計畫和實幹是兩件不同的事情
Maybe we should get there ahead, get up to Olney.
也許我們應該提前去 奧爾尼
Early bird gets the worm.
早起的鳥兒有蟲吃
- Slow down. - I ain't speeding.
- 慢點 - 我沒有超速
I found these coins in the barn.
我在穀倉裡找到這些硬幣
Lord knows how long they've been sitting there.
上帝知道它們在那裡多長時間了
I've been living off an inmate's diet,
我一直活得很清苦
and had all these coins
守著這些硬幣
sitting right underneath a bunch of feed sacks.
就在一堆飼料袋的下面
This one says 1953.
上面寫著1953年
1953?
1953年？
I wonder if any of these is collector's items.
我覺得也許有些收藏價值
You could be sitting on a fortune here.
你也許坐擁寶藏呢
I hope so.
我希望吧
Good morning, folks. Open the drawer!
早上好 夥計們 打開抽屜
Open the motherfucking drawer!
打開該死的抽屜！
Ones, fives, 10s, 20s, no hundreds, no bundles.
要1塊 5塊 10塊 20塊的 不要成百成捆的
You boys robbing the bank?
你們這些孩子搶銀行？
Shut up.
閉嘴
Put your hands on the counter. On the counter.
把你的手放在櫃檯上
Yes, sir. That's it, come on.
是的 先生 就那樣
That's crazy, y'all ain't even Mexicans.
瘋了 你們甚至都不是墨西哥人
No bundles. Just loose cash.
不要成捆的 只要零鈔
Okay.
好的
You ought to be ashamed of yourselves.
你們應該感到羞恥
Hands on the counter where I can see them!
手放在櫃檯上我能看到的地方
Yes, sir.
是的 先生
You got a gun on you, old man?
老頭 你帶槍了？
You're damn right I got a gun on me.
你說對了 我帶槍了
- Are you gonna get his gun? - Yeah.
- 你要繳他的槍？- 是的
Keep up with the circumstances, okay?
看清形勢 好嗎？
Yeah, I got it.
我找到了
So y'all gonna steal my gun, too?
你們連我的槍也偷？
I have my own gun.
我自己有槍
We ain't stealing from you. We're stealing from the bank.
我們不會偷你的 我們只是偷銀行
Much obliged.
承蒙關照
Let's go!
快走
We're sorry about this, folks.
我們很抱歉 夥計們
Dirty, rotten sons of bitches.
骯髒的婊子養的
Fuck you, old man!
F你 老頭！
Go, run, go!
走 走
Put the gun on the counter.
把槍放在櫃檯
You trying to get us killed?
你想要害死我們嗎？
I ain't stealing from some old man.
我不會偷一個老人的
We're stealing from one place, that's it.
我們偷一個機構 就那樣
You're turning out to be a poor-ass criminal.
你正在變成一個可憐的罪犯
Oh, fuck you.
哦 去你的
See what the early bird gets?
看早起的鳥得到了什麼？
Maybe we should hit that branch in jayton?
也許我們應該搶傑頓的那一家銀行？
No, we ain't. We hit those banks
不 我們搶那些銀行
first thing in the fucking morning, when they're empty.
早晨第一件事 他們還沒錢
When they're empty, god damn it.
他們還沒錢就去搶 真該死
All right.
是的
It's the last time I care to be shot at.
這應該是我們最後一次被槍打
We got to be smart. We're a ways from being finished.
我們應該聰明點 我們隨時會完蛋
Shit, I can do this all week.
我能整周都做這個
We're gonna.
我們會的
We're like the comanches, little brother,
我們喜歡克曼奇 小兄弟
raiding where we please
我們想搶哪兒就搶哪兒
with the whole of Texas hunting our shadow.
讓整個德州都在我們的籠罩之下
Lord of the plains.
主的平原
- Hands off. - Fuck off!
- 拿開手 - 去你的
You hear about these bank robberies?
你聽說過這些銀行搶劫案嗎？
Why are you always dressed like me?
為什麼你穿的和我一樣？
This is our uniform.
這是制服
We ain't got no uniform.
我們沒有制服
You can wear whatever color shirt you choose.
你盡可以穿自己喜歡的顏色
You just keep choosing mine.
你正好選了我的顏色
Ranger regs say white, blue, or tan dress shirts.
遊騎兵條例要求是白色 藍色或黃色襯衫
Stands to reason every once in a while
基於這個理由
we're gonna be dressed the same.
我們將會穿的一樣
Well, you know what they say about imitation, Alberto.
好吧 你知道什麼是模仿吧 阿爾貝托？
You wanna hear about these bank robberies,
你到底要不要聽這個銀行搶劫的案子
or you just sit there and let Alzheimer's run its course.
或者你就乾脆坐著 讓老年癡呆查案子
Where are they at?
發生在哪裡？
Texas Midlands.Branch in Archer city and the branch in Olney.
德州米德蘭茲銀行 在阿奇爾城的分行 還有奧爾尼的分行
FBI want an assist?
FBI需要協查麼
Midlands ain't got any branches outside Texas.
米德蘭茲銀行在德州以外沒有分行
Plus, they're just hitting the drawers for a few thousand.
此外 他們只拿抽屜裡的現金 也就幾千塊
FBI don't want it.
FBI看不上
You may get to have some fun
你也許可以找點樂子
before they send you off to the rocking chair yet.
在他們把你送上輪椅之前
I need you sober.
我需要你保持戒酒
Who the hell gets drunk off a beer?
誰喝光了這瓶啤酒？
Place looks like shit.
這裡爛透了
You got anything else you wanna say?
你還有別的話說麼？
There's not a decent steak
連個好的牛排館也沒有
in the whole lot of them, the sorry sons of bitches.
這個地方到處都是混蛋
Yeah, well, while you were busy in jail,
是的 當你忙著坐牢的時候
I was busy looking after mama,
我一直忙著照顧媽媽
so you can go fuck yourself.
所以你就能瞎搞
Was she in that bed a while?
她在那個床上躺了多久？
Three months.
3個月
The end there was pretty rough.
最後相當難受
I could've helped out a little if she asked.
即便她要求 我也幾乎幫不上忙
I could've fed them skinny cows.
我也不會喂皮包骨頭的牛
We had nothing to feed them.
我們也沒有飼料喂它們
Well, I could've helped clean up the house a bit.
好吧 我能幫忙收拾一下屋子
I never took you for the go-to guy for house cleaning.
我不會帶著你去打掃屋子的
No.Just robbing banks.
不 只是搶銀行
Yeah.
是的
Fuck her. She never wanted nothing to do with me anyway.
去她的 反正她從來也不待見我
She leave a will?
她有什麼遺願？
Yeah.
有
Am I in it?
有我的份嗎？
The will don't matter.
沒有
She left everything to me.
她把一切都給了我
By Friday it all goes to my boys.
週五 我就把它給我的兒子了
She didn't mean nothing by it.
這個並不說明什麼
She damn sure meant it.
這說明了一切
She always hated me for standing up to him.
她一直恨我 因為我支持他
We all got punished.
我們都得到了懲罰
You never understood that fighting back makes the beating last longer.
你總是不明白 反抗越激烈她打你的時間就越長
No, I understood.
不 我理解
That's why I stopped fighting and shot that son of a bitch.
那就是為什麼我停止了反擊 然後向那個混蛋開槍
Hey, what's going on?
發生什麼事情了？
Somebody robbed the bank this morning.
今天早上有人搶了銀行
Do what?
幹了什麼？
If you see anyone looking a little sideways, give me a call.
如果你看到可疑的人 給我電話
Sideways don't wanna meet me.
壞事一般都不找我
Find itself on the wrong end of a short rope.
那明擺著是不安全的
Oh, well, that would simplify things for everyone but you.
那大家都幹的事 你也例外
Maybe, if you can find the tree.
也許 如果你能找到一棵樹的話
God, i love west Texas.
上帝 我愛死西德州了
- Ranger? - Hi there.
- 遊騎兵？- 嗨 是的
Wasn't much of a robbery,
不是大額搶劫案
got off with just under $7, 000.
數額在7000美元以下
Took the drawer money, 20s and under,
僅僅拿了抽屜裡的錢 面值都小於20塊
only loose bills.
只是一些零鈔
- No ink pack? - Nope.
- 沒有墨水的？- 沒有
- Smart. - That was smart.
- 聰明 - 真是聰明
Can we get a look at the video?
能看一下監控錄影嗎？
Let me introduce you to the bank manager, Mr. clauson.
讓我帶你找銀行經理 克勞森先生
This here is ranger Hamilton.
這是遊騎兵漢密爾頓
- Ranger. - Sir.
- 我是遊騎兵 - 先生
Can we get a look at the surveillance video?
能看一下監控錄影嗎？
We got cameras,
我們有個攝像頭
but they're switching us over to a digital system
但是他們給換成數位系統了
that feeds into the computer.
記錄到電腦裡
These new cameras don't hook to our vcrs.
這些新的攝像頭 沒有和我們的錄影機相連
Call over the young county sheriffs.
打電話給楊縣的警長
Ask them if they thought to hook their cameras
問他們是否知道 怎麼調取監控
to some sort of recording device.
或者有類似的錄影設備
- Armed? - Yes, sir. Pistols.
- 他們帶武器了麼 - 是的 先生 手槍
Faces covered?
蒙面？
Ski masks, sweatshirts, baggy pants...
滑雪面罩 套頭衫 休閒褲……
Uh-huh. Like them thugs in Dallas.
就像達拉斯的那些暴徒
Tweakers maybe?
也許是吸毒的？
Maybe.
也許
A little early in the morning for tweakers.
對那些吸毒的人來說 有點早
Tweakers don't sleep. They just tweak.
吸毒的不睡覺 就是吸
They rob drug stores and parked cars, not banks.
他們搶劫藥店和路邊的車 而不是銀行
Can I take a look inside?
我能看看裡面嗎？
Yes, sir.
可以 先生
Yeah, I'm here, Margaret.
好的 我來了 瑪格麗特
So they bopped you on the schnozzola, huh?
他們給了你鼻子一拳 是嗎？
Yes, sir.
是的 先生
Not very nice.
不好受吧
I know their faces was covered,
我知道他們蒙面
but could you tell their race?
但是你能說出他們的種族嗎？
Black, white?
黑人 白人？
Their skin or their souls?
他們的皮膚還是他們的靈魂？
Let's leave their souls out of this for now.
讓我們暫時不管他們的靈魂
White.
白人
From around here somewhere is my guess,
我猜就是附近的人
you know, from their voices.
聽口音
Young county says same deal
楊縣也發生了同樣的事情
with the branch in Olney.
位於奧爾尼的分行
Excuse me.
抱歉
Do they have video?
他們有監控嗎？
Same deal all the way around.
設備都一樣
Doesn't Walmart sell all sorts of electronic equipment?
沃爾瑪賣的不是一樣的電子設備？
My word. Get your hands off that.
要我說 別寫了
Well, these boys, they aren't done yet, I'll tell you that.
好吧 這些傢伙 應該不會收手
- How come? - Well, they're patient.
- 為什麼那麼說？- 他們很有耐心
Just sticking to the drawers,
只是拿抽屜的錢
not taking the hundreds, that's the bank's money,
不拿百元大鈔 那是銀行的錢
we can trace that.
我們能追蹤到這些錢
They're trying to raise a certain amount, that's my guess.
他們想要湊夠一定的數額 我猜測
It's gonna take a few banks to get there.
他們需要多搶幾家
Your boys know how rich they're gonna be?
你們知道他們能多有錢嗎？
They don't know anything yet.
他們還什麼都不知道
You take them to the funeral?
你帶他們去的葬禮？
Like I said, they don't know anything.
我說過了 他們什麼也不知道
When's the last time you saw them?
你上次是什麼時候見的他們？
When we all went to the rodeo in stamford right after you got out.
你出來以後 我們一起去斯坦福市看表演的時候
That was a year ago. I talk to them on the phone.
那是大約一年前 我電話裡和他們談的
You talk to them on the phone?
你通過電話和他們談的？
- You want a little advice? - No. No, I don't.
- 你需要一點建議嗎？- 不 我不需要
Go see them tomorrow.
明天去看看他們
You got any idea how much I owe Debbie in child support?
你知道我欠黛比多少撫養費嗎？
You've got enough in your front pocket
你給的已經夠多了
to fix that problem right now.
現在立刻解決這個問題
We can't spare it, you know that.
我們不能浪費它 你知道的
Maybe we should hit another branch.
也許我們應該搶另外一家銀行
You know, you talk like we ain't gonna get away with this.
你說的好像我們不能擺脫這一切似的
I've never met nobody who got away with anything, ever. You?
我從來沒有遇到過能擺脫這一切的人 你呢？
Then why in the hell did you agree to do it?
那麼你到底為什麼同意幹呢？
Because you asked, little brother.
因為你開口了 小弟
I got to shit like an old goat.
我去個廁所
Grab the check, meet me out front.
拿著支票 前門見
Well, if that isn't a hint,
如果那不是一個暗示的話
I don't know what is.
我不知道怎麼回事
You like your steak?
喜歡你的牛排嗎？
Yes, ma'am.
是的 夫人
Well, you've got a ways to go yet.
好吧 你已經找到一個離開的方法了
Yeah, you'll be waiting around all day for me to finish this.
你要一直等我們吃完
I'll be here whether you finish it or not. So...
我會一直在這裡 不管你吃不吃完
You take your time.
所以 不用著急
It sure is quiet in here.
別出聲
Open the drawer. Fives, 10s, 20s.
打開抽屜 給我5塊的 10塊的 20塊的
Fan them out like a deck of cards.
就像洗牌一樣把它們挑出來
What do you do?
你是幹什麼的？
Last job was for a...
上一份工作是……
Natural gas company.
天然氣公司
Sounds high-dollar.
聽上去掙得不少
No, there ain't nothing high-dollar about drilling.
幹鑽探的掙不著錢
No one seems to be drilling for gas now, anyway.
現在沒人鑽探天然氣了
They sure drilling for oil.
他們都在鑽石油了
I mean, ain't one drill the same as the next?
我的意思是 沒人會總是鑽探一種東西的
That's my take on it.
看來是我的問題了
I guess, I got to get someone else to believe me.
我猜 我得讓別人相信我
Son of a bitch!
混蛋
We could use a cook.
我們需要個廚師
Just a thought.
想到什麼說什麼了
Order's up, Jenny Ann.
上菜 珍妮 安
Bye.
再見
Start the car!
發動汽車
Shit.
該死
Fuck! Shit!
Go, go, go!
快走
I bet you don't owe this much in child support.
我打賭這次你不欠孩子的撫養費了
I must be out of my goddamn mind to ask you for help.
我一定是腦子進水了 才找你幫忙
You wanna get us killed? Huh?
你想要害死我們嗎？
That's not a Midlands branch.
那個不是米德蘭茲銀行
That's not part of the plan.
那不是計畫中的
Now, we got to go back to the ranch and bury the car. Fuck!
現在 我們得回農場埋掉汽車 該死！
No, we do not. We're over halfway to Oklahoma.
不 我們不用 還有一半路就到奧克拉荷馬州了
I'm not driving a stolen getaway car
我不要開一輛偷來的車
to a fucking Indian casino.
去印第安賭場
You just put us a goddamn day behind.
你讓我們晚了一天
Well, I got us a day ahead this morning, so I guess we're even.
今早我讓我們提前了一天 扯平了
- You're welcome. - Fuck you.
- 你該說謝謝 - 去你的
Can't you answer your own phone?
你就不能接一下電話？
I'm driving.You're just sitting there twiddling your fat fingers.
我在開車呢 而你坐在一邊掰指頭
Ranger Hamilton's phone.
遊騎兵漢密爾頓的電話
It's reckless is what it is. Oh...
真是太魯莽了…
It's tweakers. I'm telling you.
是吸毒的 我說過
I don't think these boys is reckless.
我不認為那些孩子是不計後果
Damn sure ain't tweakers.
絕對不是吸毒的
They know exactly what they're doing.
他們清楚地知道自己在做什麼
I don't know how you're gonna survive
我不知道你是怎麼活下來的
without somebody to outsmart.
如果沒人幫你想事情的話
You need a hobby, and quick.
你需要一個愛好
How about a horse?
來一匹馬怎麼樣？
Mary Beth was the rider.
瑪麗貝絲是騎師
A horse would only remind me of her.
看到馬只能讓我想起她
You like to fish.
你應該去釣魚
Not enough to do it every goddamn day.
也不能天天去釣魚啊
Yeah, when I retire,
我退休以後
I'm gonna move Esme and me down to galveston.
我要和埃斯梅一起搬到加爾維斯頓去
Buy a fishing boat.
買一艘漁船
Gonna live on that son of a bitch right at the pier.
就生活在碼頭上
Oh, who knows?
誰知道呢？
Maybe one of these bank robbers
也許其中一個銀行搶匪
is gonna want a gunfight,
想要來一場槍戰
and I can dodge my retirement in a Blaze of glory.
我就能戴著榮譽勳章退休了
Well, I've seen you shoot.
我看過你開槍
There won't be much glory in it.
你肯定得不了勳章
Oh, well, I'm lucky
好吧 我運氣好
I got a half-breed by my side to avenge me.
印第安兄弟們站在我一邊 會幫我復仇的
If you can stay sober long enough.
如果你能保持清醒的話
Knowing how you injuns like the bottle.
知道你們印第安人多喜歡酒
Hey. What you all doing?
你究竟在幹什麼？
You burning this field?
你在燒荒嗎？
Why in the shit would we do that?
我們為什麼要這麼做？
This kicked up on the highway,
這是高速公路引發的
been chasing us ever since.
從那時起就一直困擾著我們
Wish we could do something for you.
希望我們能為你做些什麼
Ought to just let it turn me to ashes
應該就讓它把我燒成灰
and put me out of my misery.
讓我不再悲催
Cut that fence.
切斷籬笆
21st century,
21世紀
I'm racing a fire to the river with a herd of cattle.
我趕著牲口和火比賽看誰先到河邊
And I wonder why my kids won't do this shit for a living.
我希望我的孩子不用以此為生
Move it. Come on.
繼續走
Go, go, go.
駕！！！
You wanna call it in?
你要報告嗎？
Oh, it's gonna burn out when it hits the brazos.
只能燒到布拉索斯河
No one to call around here, anyway.
反正這附近也沒有人住
These boys is on their own.
這些孩子都靠自己
I still don't see the problem, Toby.
我沒看出有什麼問題 托比
You still don't...
你還沒有
Well, the problem is, thanks to you
問題是 拜你所賜
we have to spend tomorrow morning getting another car,
我們明天得花一個早上 才能再找到一輛車
so we'll have to hit two banks on Wednesday.
所以我們週三必須搶兩家銀行
We already done three today.
我們今天已經做了三個了
Stop worrying.
別擔心
Whose land is this?
這是誰的土地？
Jeremy chalker.
傑瑞米 巧克
He lets me stay here in exchange for shooting coyotes.
他收留我 我則幫他射土狼
Cold beer in the fridge.
冰箱裡有冰啤酒
You stole my hat.
你偷了我的帽子
I borrowed it.
我借的
What the fuck you do to it?
究竟你對它做了什麼？
- What's this? - My livelihood.
- 這是什麼？- 我的營生
We don't need all this.
我們不需要這麼多
Can't keep the guns in the trailer days on end.
最後不能把槍留在拖車裡
That's not coming with us in the bank.
不能帶著這個去銀行
Just spoke to the teller.
剛剛和出納談過
She's a little shook up.
她受了點驚嚇
Perp took her driver's license,
嫌犯拿走了她的駕照
threatened her family if she talked to us.
威脅如果她報警 就會對家人不利
Mind if I ask you your name, young lady?
我能知道你的名字嗎 女士
Natalie Martinez.
娜塔莉 瑪丁尼
Well, Natalie, i want you to know
好吧 娜塔莉 我希望你知道
we're gonna have some officers
我們會派一些警官
watching your house, extra careful,
保護你的家 非常的用心
till we catch these buggers.
直到我們抓住這些搶匪
You have my word on that.
我說話算話
There's more than one?
難道不止一個人嗎？
Only one man robbed the bank?
只有一個人搶銀行？
- Yeah. - What'd he look like?
- 是一個人 - 他什麼樣子？
He was dressed like a cowpoke except for the ski mask.
他穿的就像個牛仔 除了戴著滑雪面罩
I think he ran to a car
我覺得他跑進了一輛汽車
that was parked out front of the diner.
就停在餐館的前門
You saw the car?
你看到了汽車？
It was green.
綠色的
- How old? - I don't know cars, mister.
- 多老的汽車？ - 我不懂車 先生
Well, was it a nice car or an okay car,
好吧 是一輛好車 還是普通車
or a real piece of shit?
或者就是一輛破車？
It was a real piece of shit.
是一輛破車
All right. Now, we're getting somewhere.
好吧 我們還是得到了一些資訊
Oh, that looks like a man who could foreclose on a house.
看起來有人在裡面接應
Excuse me, Natalie.
打擾啦 娜塔莉
Excuse me, Mr. banker.
打擾啦 銀行家先生
Natalie, I'm gonna have the officer stay with you, Natalie.
我會安排一個警官保護你的 娜塔莉
till your father arrives, all right?
直到你父親過來 好吧？
Okay.
好的
Didn't happen to have your surveillance cameras
請問有沒有今天早上的
on this morning, did you?
監控錄影？
Of course.
當然有
Oh, so you have the robbery on video.
這麼說你有劫匪的錄影
Of course we do.
當然有
What kind of bank would we be
我們這種銀行當然有
if we didn't have video surveillance?
能看一下監控嗎？
Oh, you'd be a Texas Midlands bank.
你們一定是德州米德蘭茲銀行
All right, we've got video.
好吧 我們有錄影了
Care to give it a watch while I wander over to the burger joint?
仔細看看錄影 我去劫匪接頭的地方
Would you order me something
你去那個餐館時
while you're there? I'm starving.
你能幫我弄點吃的嗎 我餓了
I doubt they serve pemmican.
我覺得他們不會有印第安幹肉餅
You know I'm part Mexican, too.
你知道我也有墨西哥血統
Yeah, well, I'm gonna get to that
好吧 我知道了
when I'm through with the Indian insults,
但是要我喜歡印第安段子
but it's gonna be a while.
還得有一陣子
You rangers are an odd bunch.
你們遊騎兵都夠怪的
No, just him. Let's take a look at that video.
就他那樣 我們看看視頻吧
Yeah, it's right back here.
好的 在後面
Howdy.
你好
Ma'am. Guess you know about the goings-on at the bank.
夫人 估計你也知道銀行發生什麼事情了吧
I did notice.
注意到了
Any out-of-towners come through today?
今天有外面來的客人嗎？
Jenny Ann waited on a couple of boys, ain't from here.
珍妮安招待了一對小夥子 不是本地人
I'll go get her.
我去喊她
Appreciate that.
非常感謝
Boys.
夥計們
Y'all been here for a while?
你們一直在這裡嗎？
Well, long enough to watch a bank getting robbed
是的 看到了整個搶劫的過程
that's been robbing me for 30 years.
那家銀行已經搶了我30多年了
Oh, you say you've seen them?
你說你看到了他們？
I'm pretty sure they were sitting
我很確定他們坐在那裡
right over there having lunch.
吃午餐
One of them was tall.
一個高一點
The other one was short.
一個矮一點
They's both lean like cowboys.
裝束都像是牛仔
Looked like brothers if you ask me.
看上去像是兄弟倆
You the Texas ranger?
你是德州遊騎兵？
Yes, ma'am.
是的 夫人
Tell me about those handsome young strangers that you waited on.
講講你招待的那些陌生帥哥
Who said handsome?
誰說他們英俊了？
I did.
我說的
Based on the fact that you didn't meet me in the parking lot,
根據你沒有沖到停車場
hollering about the two out-of-towners
向我大聲叫喊有兩個外地人
eating here right before a bank robbery.
搶銀行之前在這裡吃飯
Well, they didn't mention they was robbing the bank.
他們沒有說要搶銀行
They pay cash?
付得現金？
That a crime now?
那也犯法嗎？
How much did they leave?
他們留下多少錢？
How much?
多少錢？
$200.
200美元
And they left it before the bank was robbed. So...
那是他們搶銀行之前留下的 所以……
Uh, before this bank was robbed.
搶銀行之前
I'm gonna need to see them bills.
我需要看看那些錢
Ma'am.
夫人
Ma'am, them bills is evidence.
夫人 那些錢是證據
Mmm-mmm. It's evidence if they're the bank robbers.
就因為是劫匪的 就是證據了
Till then, it's my tip.
目前為止 它是我的小費
And half my mortgage.
我一半的房貸
So, you go out there and you get a warrant, and come after the money
所以 你去拿搜查證 再來取錢
that I will be using to keep a roof over my daughter's head.
這錢能保證我女兒有地方住
One man hit the bank, just like she said.
一個人搶了銀行 的確如她所說
Yeah. Checkered button-down shirt,
花格子襯衫
jeans, ski mask. It's on the videotapes.
牛仔褲 滑雪面罩 都在視頻裡
Checkered shirt.That was him.
花格子襯衫 就是他
They were sitting right over there. Tipped her $200.
他們就坐在那裡 給了200元的小費
Go wrestle a description from that big sassy girl in the kitchen.
去廚房和那個蠻橫的胖妞印證一下
You didn't get it yourself?
你自己怎麼不去？
Oh, and get that tip from her. We're gonna check them bills.
拿到那些小費 我們需要檢查那些鈔票
Good luck.
祝你好運
Yeah, I'd expect some resistance.
祝你成功
Oh, and, Alberto,
另外 阿爾貝托
call that motel on 287, get us a room.
給旅館打電話訂個房間
We're gonna stay the night?
我們要在這裡過夜？
Well, this is where the action is.
對 這裡是案發現場
Seems foolish.
看著挺蠢的
What's that?
什麼？
The days of robbing banks
大白天的搶銀行
and trying to live, spend the money.
努力生活 花錢
They've long gone.
他們早就跑遠了
Long gone for sure.
肯定跑遠了
What does Justin want to do when he's grown?
賈斯汀長大了想做什麼？
Right now he's dreaming of slinging a football for a&m.
目前為止夢想打橄欖球
He's a lot like you.
他很像你
I bet that puckers your red eye.
我敢打賭 你肯定氣紅了眼
More than you know.
還不止呢
Thirty-nine years of life,
39年的人生
10 in jail. If he turns left where I turned right, he'll be okay.
10年在牢裡 只要他不學我 就肯定沒事
You want anything?
你要什麼？
Dr. pepper, Winston lights.
二鍋頭和清酒
It's okay. Come on.
沒事的 別怕
What?
怎麼了？
What, bitch?
什麼 混蛋？
You looking for trouble, motherfucker?
你要找事嗎？混蛋？
You came to the right place.
你來對地方了
Boy, you'd think there were 10 of me.
孩子 我能打你十個
Oh, yeah?
是嗎？
Not so fucking tough now, are you, bitch?
不要那麼硬 混蛋？
Hey, man, he had it coming.
嗨 夥計 不管我事
He had it coming.
不管我事
You got some spunk left in you.
你夠勇的啊
Oh, you remembered the gun!
這次你沒有忘了槍！
You're getting to be old hat at this.
吃一塹長一智啊
Asshole could've killed you.
混蛋可能會殺了你
Ah, not the way it would have gone, little brother.
沒事的 老弟
Ten of me, I told you.
打你十個 我告訴過你
Are you trying to make me mad?
你要逼瘋我嗎？
I said Dr. pepper, this is Mr. pibb.
我要的是二鍋頭 這是大麯
That's all they had.
他們就只有這個
Only assholes drink Mr. pibb.
啥子才喝大麯呢
Drink up.
你就喝了吧
Now we're talking.
現在我們聊聊
The women in this place.
這裡的女人啊
What the hell you talking about?
你究竟在聊什麼啊？
We should get another shot, they'll be pretty soon enough.
我們應該再喝一杯
Bartender, whiskeys if you please.
酒保 威士卡 謝謝
Coming up.
來吧
To your boys.
給你兒子
Let's go change that money.
我們去換錢
Sorry. I just sold my car. This is how the fella paid me.
對不起 我剛剛賣了車 那傢伙拿這些付我
We take it any way you bring it, mister.
什麼錢我們都收 先生
Wanna play some poker?
想要玩撲克嗎？
I don't gamble.
我不賭博
You can't lose at poker, not even you.
你連撲克都輸不起
I'm gonna watch the aggie game and have a beer.
我會看彈球 喝啤酒
Suit yourself.
隨你
Come on now.
別啊
Suck a d.
給我啊
Don't lose it all.
別都輸了
Eat my a.
去你的
Fucking asshole.
該死的傢伙
That's, uh, quite a stack.
那 好大一堆
Check?
跟嗎
Don't chase me, chief.
別跟我 酋長
You comanche?
你是卡曼奇族的？
Lords of the plains.
主的平原
Lords of nothing now.
主現在什麼都沒有了
I call.
我叫
Show your cards, gentlemen.
亮牌 先生們
Do you know what comanche means?
你知道卡曼奇什麼意思嗎？
It means enemies forever.
意味著永遠的敵人
Enemies with who?
與誰為敵？
Everyone.
所有的人
You know what that makes me?
你知道什麼成就了我嗎？
An enemy.
敵人
No.
不
It makes me a comanche.
它讓我成為了卡曼奇
Does he look like you?
他像你嗎？
I see his mom in him,
我看他像他媽媽
everybody else sees me.
別人看著像我
I don't know.
我不知道
You staying in the hotel?
你住在這個酒店？
Yeah.
是的
Take me to your room.
帶我到你的房間
Thank you. Just, uh...
謝謝你 但是
You know, there's no shame in needing the touch of a woman.
要知道 摸女人沒有什麼值得羞恥的
You need it.
你需要它
I know you do.
我知道你需要
Just let me touch you.
讓我來撫摸你
Are you trying to work my little brother?
你想要釣我的兄弟嗎？
No, I wasn't doing anything, but I'm...
不 我沒幹什麼
Tanner, she didn't do nothin'.
泰納 她沒做什麼
She didn't do nothin'. But, but, but, but, but...
她沒有做什麼 但是 但是……
You saw there was a stack of chips, here.
你看到那裡有一堆籌碼
- Easy mark? - Don't.
- 想佔便宜？- 不是
Uh... no.
哦……不
What were you gonna do? Bring him up to his room,
你要怎麼做？跟他回房間
call your pimp,
然後把你的皮條客叫來
- roll him, drug him, what? - No. I...
- 勒索他？- 不是
- What were you gonna do? - Tanner, don't.
- 你要幹什麼？ - 泰納 不要
Mind if I sample the goods? Real...
介意我試試貨嗎？
Hands off her. Stop it. Stop it.
放開她 住手
You're fucking crazy.
你個瘋子
Call me.
你來啊
We got a problem here...
我這裡有情況…
- It's all good. - It's all good.
- 沒事了 - 沒事了
It's all good. Just got a little drunk
沒事了 喝多了
at the bar, sorry about that.
在吧台喝的 抱歉
How the fuck have you managed
你到底是怎麼
to stay out of prison for a year?
在監獄外面待了一年的
It's been difficult.
很艱難
Like to pay this out in cash or check?
要兌換現金還是支票？
Get some Debbie money.
給黛比帶些錢
Four in cash, rest in check.
四成現金 其餘的支票。
Who would you like the check made out to?
你希望在哪裡支取？
Texas Midlands bank.
德州米德蘭茲銀行
Thank you much.
非常感謝
Let's go get a room.
我們訂個房間
Welcome to the comanche 66. Do you have a reservation?
歡迎來到卡曼奇66旅店 請問有沒有預訂。
We do not.
沒有預訂
Good lord, look at you.
神啊 看看你
We would be obliged if you would provide accommodations,
若能提供房間 我們感激涕零
though we failed to call ahead.
冒昧未能提前預約
Boy, you are trouble.
夥計 你攤上事兒了
Oh, the worst kind, darling.
最糟的那種 親愛的
In your last days in the nursing home,
在你的彌留之際
you'll think of me and giggle.
你將能想起我 和我的笑聲
Why, god,
為什麼 上帝
why won't you answer my prayers?
為什麼你 沒有回應我的禱告
You begged him for help,
你祈求他的幫助
and yet you look around at your life
然而回顧你的一生
and nothing is different.
沒有什麼不同
And so you assume that god has told you no.
所以你假設上帝對你說不
God doesn't say no.
上帝沒有說不
Why couldn't we drive back to lubbock?
為什麼我們不回拉伯克市？
They ain't robbing banks in lubbock.
他們不會搶劫拉伯克的銀行
We're not gonna watch this, are we?
為什麼我們非要看這個節目？
Ain't you Christian?
難道你不是基督徒？
Yeah. But I ain't stupid.
是 但我不是傻瓜
God doesn't talk through this man
上帝才不會通過這個人說話
any more than he talks through my dog.
寧可通過我的狗
Well, then maybe you should give your dog a listen.
好吧 你應該給你的狗受洗
Ain't you Indian?
你不是印第安人？
You're supposed to be burning Sage
你應該是被火燒的聖人
and dancing around the bed whooping like a bee stung you.
繞著床起舞 像一群嗡嗡的蜜蜂
I'm catholic.
我是天主教徒
Come on.
你拉倒吧
Come on! I'd rather dance around a fire with a spear.
少來 我寧可拿著長矛圍著火堆跳舞
I'd rather have you stab me with a spear than watch this.
我寧可你用長矛紮我 也不想要看這個
This son of a bitch, he wouldn't know god
這個混蛋 根本不懂上帝
if he crawled up his pant leg and bit him on the pecker.
他就是個混蛋
Change the damn channel.
趕緊換台
Now, this, this is what god watches right here.
看這個 就看這個
Don't worry, they're gonna have soccer highlights on soon enough.
不用擔心 他們很快就播足球集錦
That's for your Mexican half.
很適合墨西哥那一半的你
Wow, look at this boy run.
哇 看這孩子跑的多快
Longhorns are gonna have a good team this year.
長角隊今年的陣容不錯
That soccer, never could understand that.
足球 永遠不能理解那個
Anything a five-year-old can do ain't a sport.
任何5歲孩子都能玩的 才不是運動
Who invented it? Aztecs?
誰發明的？阿茲特克人
Kickin' around skulls or something, right?
先是踢頭骨之類的是嗎？
Sounds like a comanche sport.
聽著像是卡曼奇人的運動
You know, in three weeks,
你知道 在三個星期裡
you can watch whatever you want on TV all day.
你可以整天看你想看的電視
Hell, you can do it right now in your own room.
夥計 你現在在自己的房間裡 怎麼都行
Oh, where's the fun in that?
那樣就沒勁了
You know what, Alberto?
你知道嗎 阿爾貝托
What?
什麼？
In a year's time,
一年的時間
it's my teasing that you're gonna miss.
你肯定會想念我的調侃的
It's what you'll laugh about
那將是你所有的笑點
when you stand over my grave and wish me well.
當你站在我的墓前 祝福我時
God, I hope that's tomorrow.
上帝 我希望那是明天
Oh, that was a good one.
那真有你的
You'll get the hang of this yet.
你會明白這個的
Isn't it getting late for you?
現在給你不遲吧？
Yeah.
是的
Yeah, it is.
Oh, heavens above. Heavens above.
蒼天在上
Look at those titties. Are you fucking kidding me?
瞧你的大波波 你是在開玩笑嗎？
What are you doing?
你在幹什麼？
Sleeping on the porch, practicing my future.
睡在走廊上 預演我的未來
It's a dangerous thing we do for a living.
我們謀生的方式是很危險的
You're lucky,
你很幸運
having seen it through to the end.
走到了終點
I hope I'm that lucky.
我希望我幸運
Oh, well.
好的
Without me by your side,
沒有我在你身邊
I doubt you'd get close enough
我懷疑你根本無法靠近罪犯
to a criminal to ever be in danger again.
總在危險之外
Just when I was starting to feel sorry for you.
剛剛我還對你有些歉疚呢
Indians ain't supposed to feel sorry for cowboys.
印第安人不應該對牛仔有歉疚
It's the other way around.
不是一回事
And this makes you the executor?
這讓你成為遺囑執行人？
No matter what they charge us with,
無論他們控告我們什麼
they can't take it away.
他們都不能拿走
There's no way to trace funds from a casino.
無法追蹤賭場的資金。
All right? Once you get the checks to the bank,
對嗎？一旦你把支票給銀行
trust is untouchable.
信託就是安全的
You can't tell nobody nothing, right?
你不能告訴別人任何資訊 對嗎？
Well, what is there to tell?
是啊 我要說什麼？
I mean, you boys won that money gambling, didn't you?
我的意思是說 你們是從賭場贏的錢 不是嗎？
$32, 000 pays off the reverse mortgage.
3萬2千元用於抵押貸款
And those bastards paid the property tax from 2012 to now,
那些混蛋支付了從2012年到現在的房產稅
that's another $11, 000.
那是1萬1千元
So, $43,000 and you are free and clear.
所以 用4萬3千元你們就自由了 清帳了
Just have the loan officer fax me a release of lien,
只要借貸員傳真給我解除抵押的檔
and I'll get that over to the lease manager at chevron.
我會交給雪佛龍公司的租賃經理
The fax number is on the card.
稅號在卡上
Okay.
好的
How much you making on this deal?
這筆交易你能賺多少？
Not near as much as I'm risking.
同風險相比沒有幾個錢
Why you doin' it then?
那你為什麼做？
You know, they loaned the least they could.
你知道 他們提供最少的貸款
Just enough to keep your mama poor on a guaranteed return.
只夠你媽媽基本歸還額
Thought they could swipe her land for $25,000.
本來打算從她的土地上再撈2萬5千元的
That's just so arrogant, it makes my teeth hurt.
囂張得讓人牙癢癢
To see you boys
看看你們
pay those bastards back with their own money?
用那些混蛋自己的錢 還給他們自己
Well, if that ain't texan, I don't know what is.
如果那不是德州人 我不知道什麼才是
Thank you.
謝謝你
Now, they can foreclose on Friday.
另外 他們週五會提前關門
Come hell or high water,
無論如何
be at the bank in childress on Thursday.
週四到柴爾德里斯的銀行
Knowing them fuckers, they will close early.
那些混蛋會提早關門
- We'll be there. - Oh, and, Toby,
- 我們會按時到的 - 另外 托比
the trust needs to be managed by a bank.
信託需要由一家銀行管理
You really wanna cover your tracks?
如果你真的要隱藏痕跡的話
You get Texas midland to handle this trust.
你可以讓德州米德蘭茲銀行託管
So,
所以
what's the plan?
什麼計畫？
We're gonna watch that bank like a deer feeder.
我們要密切關注那銀行
In time, we'll be right.
及時 我們會沒事的
Now, let's see what they got to eat here.
現在 讓我們看看這裡有什麼吃的
Howdy, ma'am. How are you doing today?
你好 夫人 今天怎麼樣？
Hot. And I don't mean the good kind.
很熱 我心情不好
So, what don't you want?
所以 你們不要什麼？
Pardon?
再說一次？
What don't you want?
你不想要什麼？
Oh, well, uh, I think I'll just, uh...
哦 好的 我覺得我要……
You know, I've been working here for 44 years.
我在這裡工作了44年了
Ain't nobody ever ordered nothing
從來沒有遇到過
but t-bone steak and a baked potato.
點排骨和烤土豆以外的人
Except this one asshole from New York
除了1987年有個從紐約來的混球
tried to order trout back in 1987.
竟然想要點鮭魚
We don't sell no goddamned trout.
我們從來不賣什麼鳥鮭魚
T-bone steaks.
只有牛排
So, either you don't want the corn on the cob,
所以 你也不要配玉米棒子
or you don't want the green beans.
你也不要綠豆子
So, what don't you want?
所以 你有什麼不要的？
I don't want green beans.
我不要綠豆子
I don't want green beans either.
我也不要綠豆子
Steaks cooked medium rare.
牛排三分熟
- Can I get my steak cooked...- That weren't no question.
- 我的牛排是否… - 不能有問題
All right.
好吧
Iced tea for you boys.
冰茶要嗎
Iced tea would be great.
冰茶當然很棒啊
Iced tea, yep. Thank you, ma'am.
也是冰茶 謝謝你 夫人
Well, I'll tell you one thing.
好 我告訴你一件事
Nobody's gonna rob this son of a bitch.
才不會有人想要搶這裡
My word.
聽我一句
How's she feel?
她怎麼樣？
She runs good.
她跑的很好
Ain't gonna win any races.
有沒有贏過什麼比賽？
Got new Mexico plates.
得過墨西哥的獎牌
She got a top?
冠軍？
That's how she came.
那就是她的來歷
We'll take her.
我們要她了
Don't report it stolen until Friday.
週五前別報警他被偷了
The guy from chevron is dropping off the lease agreement.
從雪佛龍來的傢伙放棄了租約
Are you okay dealing with that by yourself?
你能自己處理嗎？
You okay being with Debbie by yourself?
你能和黛比好好待著嗎？
Remember, he ain't the enemy.
記住 他不是敵人
Just take the papers, and say thank you.
只要接過檔 說謝謝
The oil man is the enemy,
石油工人是敵人
make no mistake. He just ain't ours.
別犯錯 他只是不和我們一夥
I'll be back to the ranch by dark.
我天黑的時候會回牧場
I will be waiting.
我會一直等著
Drive like a schoolteacher with all this shit in the back.
為了後備箱裡的那些玩意兒 要像老師一樣規矩開車
Sure feels like beer o'clock.
好像到了啤酒時間了
Ask and you shall receive.
請求並希望能接受
Come in.
進來
Mama died.
媽媽死了
When?
什麼時候？
A few weeks ago.
幾周之前
Well, good riddance.
總算解脫了
No offense.
沒有別的意思
You okay?
你還好嗎？
You?
你呢？
Here's the money I owe you.
這些錢 是我欠你的
I guess you'll be selling the ranch.
我猜你會賣掉牧場
It goes to the boys.
已經轉給兒子了
Really?
真的？
It's been put in a trust.
已經放在了一個信託裡了
What's that mean?
什麼意思？
It means no one can sell it.
意味著沒有人能賣掉它
Great. Something else I got to take care of.
太好了 我又多了樣需要照看的事情了
Where's your brother?
你兄弟在哪裡？
I don't know.
我不知道
Friend's house, I guess.
朋友家吧 我猜
How come you ain't in school?
你怎麼沒有去上學？
School don't start yet.
還沒有開學
Just two-a-days for football right now.
現在一天兩次足球課
Your grandmother died.
你奶奶死了
I'm giving the ranch to you and your brother.
我把牧場留給了你和你兄弟
Remember going out there when you was little?
你小的時候去過那裡 還記得嗎？
What am I supposed to do with a ranch?
我該拿一個農場怎麼辦？
Anything but sell it.
除了出售 幹什麼都行
We found oil on it.
我們在那裡發現了油
You and your brother ain't gonna have to worry about money no more.
你和你兄弟 再不用擔心錢的問題
Now,
現在
you may be hearing a lot of things about me
你可能聽說很多我的事情
and your uncle.
還有你伯伯的
Don't be like us.
不要像我們一樣
You hear me?
你聽到我的話了？
Whatever I hear, i won't believe.
不管我聽到什麼 我都不會相信的
No, you believe it.
不 你信的
I did all of it.
都是我幹的
Now, you, you do it different.
現在你要做一些不同的事情
Ain't gonna drink it?
不喝酒？
You tell me not to be like you,
你讓我不要像你一樣
and then you offer me a beer.
但是卻讓我喝啤酒？
Which is it?
哪句是真的？
Good boy.
好孩子
How are the boys? What are you doin'?
孩子們怎麼樣？你在幹什麼？
Insurance.
保險
I don't want that shit in the car.
我不要那個東西
We'll be running two cars next time, brother.
下次我們要開兩輛車
They'll ride with me.
我會帶著它們
So, this is your plan?
這就是你的計畫？
We're just gonna sit here
我們就是坐在這裡
and see if this is the branch they rob next.
看這家銀行是否是他們的下一個目標
What would you rather do?
那你想要做什麼？
You wanna drive 80 miles back to olney
你想開車80英里回奧爾尼
and look for more fingerprints that we ain't gonna find?
找找我們沒有發現的指紋？
Or you wanna drive 200 miles back to lubbock
或者開車200英里回拉伯克
and look at mug shots that don't matter
看看那些根本不重要的槍擊
because nobody knows what these sons of bitches look like.
因為沒有人知道 這些龜兒子長什麼樣子
Or we can just wait here for them to rob this bank,
或者我們坐在這裡 等他們搶劫這家銀行
which is the one thing I'm pretty damn sure they are going to do.
這是唯一我能確定他們會做的事情
I know what you're doing.
我知道你在幹什麼
You're trying to make this last as long as you can because the longer it lasts,
你想儘量延長這次任務
the farther you are from that front porch.
它持續越久 就能遲點退休
No, I'm waitin' for these boys to make a mistake.
不 我在等這些孩子犯錯
So far they ain't, but they will.
目前為止他們還沒有 但是他們會的
And they're gonna make it here.
他們會在這裡犯錯的
So, just relax.
所以 放鬆一些
Enjoy this little town.
享受一下這個小鎮子
Do you wanna live here?
你想要住在這裡嗎？
Got an old hardware store that charges twice what home depot does,
只有一個老商店
one restaurant with a rattlesnake for a waitress.
一個蛇鼠做窩的餐館和一個老招待
I mean, how is anybody supposed to make a living here?
我的意思是 怎麼會有人願意在這裡生活？
People have made a living here for 150 years.
人們已經在這裡生活了150年了
Well, people lived in caves for 150, 000 years.
好吧 人類已經在洞穴裡生活了15萬年了
But they don't do it no more.
但是他們不想再那麼生活了
Well, maybe your people did.
當然 也許你的人民不那麼想
Your people did, too.
你的人民也是一樣
A long time ago, your ancestors was the Indians,
很久以前 你的祖先是印第安人
till someone came along and killed them,
直到有人來殺了他們
broke 'em down, made you into one of them.
打倒了他們 使得你成為了他們的一員
150 years ago, all of this was my ancestors' land.
150年前 所有的這些都是我的祖先的土地
Everything you could see.
你能看到的所有的一切
Everything you saw yesterday.
昨天你能看到的所有一切
Till the grandparents of these folks took it.
直到這些傢伙們的父輩們掠奪了它
And now, it's been taken from them.
而現在 又從他們手裡被奪走了
Except it ain't no army doing it.
只是不再用軍隊了
It's those sons of bitches right there.
而是那邊那些龜兒子
You thinking about tomorrow?
你想過明天嗎？
Ain't you?
你沒有嗎？
That little hotel clerk.
那個小旅館店員
Why is it always the sweet ones
為什麼總是最甜美的
that are such devils when you get them revved up?
當你弄得她們爽歪歪時
Wouldn't know, never had a sweet one.
不知道 從來沒有遇見過甜美的
Yeah, you like them pissed off,
你總喜歡她們生氣的模樣
lookin' for someone to blame.
老想找人出氣
Sure seems that way.
還真的是那樣
It's a good thing you're doing.
你正在做的是好事
We're doing it.
我們一起做的
Go easy on the bank teller tomorrow.
明天對銀行出納別太凶
I'll be as gentle as a young nurse.
我會像年輕護士一樣的溫柔
You coming?
你來嗎？
On my way.
按照我的方式
Shit.
該死
Good morning.
早上好
You want some breakfast?
你要吃早餐嗎？
Yeah, breakfast sounds good.
是的 來份早餐不錯
So we hit the jayton branch first, then Coleman, right?
所以我們先到傑頓分行 然後科爾曼分行 對嗎？
Yeah, that should get us what we need.
那樣應該就能湊夠數了
Let's do this.
讓我們做這個吧
Ugh... shit.
該死
That's not part of the fucking plan.
那可不在計畫之列
Bastards closed down the branch.
混蛋們關掉了分行
What now, little brother?
怎麼辦 兄弟？
Coleman.
去科爾曼分行
What the hell you doing?
你究竟在做什麼？
We gotta head to post.
我們應該去波士特
What the hell you doing? Get...
你究竟在幹什麼？
We got to head to post. What are you talking about?
我們應該去波士特 你到底在說什麼？
We got to head to post.
我們應該去波士特
We're going to Coleman.
我們要去科爾曼
There's only one teller in Coleman.
在科爾曼只有一個出納
Whatever we get won't be enough.
無論如何我們都無法得到足夠的錢
We go to Coleman right now.
我們現在去科爾曼
If that ain't enough, we head to post.
如果還是湊不夠 我們再去波士特
If we don't leave now for post,
如果我們現在不去波士特
we won't get there till noon.
那麼我們到中午才能到那裡
You don't wanna rob a bank at lunchtime, do you?
你不會在午餐時間搶銀行吧？
Yeah, we don't know the patterns of folks out there.
是的 我們還不瞭解那裡人的活動規律
The patterns are the same everywhere.
各地的規律都是一樣的
All these towns are dead. Post ain't no different.
所有這些鎮子都死氣沉沉 波士特也不例外
It's a bigger bank.
那是一家更大的銀行
We'll leave your car just out of town.
我們把你的車留在城外
Come on now.
現在過來
Shit.
該死
I think I got this figured.
我覺得我明白了
First two banks, they were Texas midland banks.
前兩家銀行 都是德州米德蘭茲銀行
All right, there are seven branches altogether.
好吧 總共有7家分行
The main branch is in fort worth.
總行在沃斯堡
They're not gonna mess with that.
他們不會去那裡搗亂的
All right? They hit the branch in olney.
對吧？他們搶了奧爾尼分行
They hit the one in Archer city.
他們搶劫了阿奇爾分行
Then there's the one here.
這裡還有一家
Which they did not hit.
他們還沒有搶劫過的
Alberto, will you please follow me?
阿爾貝托 你願意跟著我嗎？
Just keep your mouth shut
只要你不說話就行
and just listen to what I'm gonna say.
只要聽我說就行了
There's the one here,
這裡有一家
then there's the one in childress.
柴爾德里斯有一家
There's the one in jayton.
傑頓有一家
That one's closed.
那家關門了
I know that one's closed!
我知道那家關門了
I know that one's closed, Alberto.
我知道那家關門了 阿爾貝托
That's my point. Jayton is closed.
我就是那個意思 傑頓那家關門了
That just leaves post.
那麼就剩下波士特分行了
They're not gonna mess with the bank in childress,
他們不會去柴爾德里斯那裡搗亂的
that's a fairly decent-sized town.
那是一個非常衰敗的城鎮
The branch in Vernon wasn't Midlands and they hit that.
維農市分行不是米德蘭茲的 但是他們卻搶劫了那裡
Yeah, one of them did. Alone.
是的 一個人單幹的
Then he ran all the way across the road to get to the car.
然後他跑到街對面 鑽進了汽車裡
I think his partner had no idea that was gonna happen.
我覺得他的搭檔不知道他要搶銀行
And what does that mean to us?
那對我們來說意味著什麼？
It means that the only branch that fits the bill is in post.
那意味著波士特分行是他們唯一要去的地方
Well, then let's go.
好吧 我們走
The town looks busy.
鎮子看起來很繁忙
Little bit.
有點
My word.
要我說
It's too big.
太大了
That's what she said.
她是這麼說過
It's no good.
不太好
Aw, this ain't your first rodeo.
這不是第一遭
Bigger bank.
更大的銀行
More money.
更多錢
Everybody, get on the fucking ground!
所有人 都趴在地上
Get on the fucking ground!
趴在地上
Young ladies, get on the fucking ground! Now!
年輕女士 趴在地上 立刻！
Sir, down! On the ground! Now!
先生 趴下！在地上！立刻！
Thank you very much.
非常感謝
Tellers stand up!
出納起立！
Open the drawers!
打開抽屜
Get down!
離開！
Take three steps back!
後退三步！
Open the fucking drawer, young lady!
打開抽屜 女士！
Are you deaf and dumb?
你是聾子還是傻子？
I said open the motherfucking drawer!
我說過了 打開抽屜
You, down!
你 趴下！
Now, step back!
現在 退後！
Very good. Someone's paying attention.
很好 注意了
Now, get on your motherfucking knees!
現在 跪下！
Stay down!
趴下！
All right.
好吧
Hey, hey, let's go!
我們走！
Call 911.
911報警
Jesus fucking Christ.
天哪 上帝
The whole goddamn town is shooting at us.
整個鎮子都在射我們
Get in the back. Get in the fucking back.
到後車廂 到後車廂
Come on, let's go, get in the car!
過來 進去 上車
Don't let them get away!
別讓他們跑了！
How you doing back there, little brother?
後面怎麼樣 兄弟？
You fucking killed them.
你殺了他們
Those concealed carry permits sure complicate a bank robbery, don't they?
這些帶槍的人 把銀行搶劫搞複雜了 是吧
It's not my fault it was payday.
不是我的錯 今天是發薪日
This has gone too far, tan.
這次太過分了
No one was supposed to fucking die.
沒有人應該死
It was them or us, take your pick.
不是他們就是我們 由你選
Yeah, go, Margaret.
好的 瑪格麗特
Texas Midlands in post has just been hit.
德州米德蘭茲的波士特分行被搶了
Ah! What did I tell you?
啊！我告訴過你什麼？
Yeah.
是的
Yeah. Locals are in chase.
本地人都在追呢
Suspects escaping west in an old bronco.
疑犯開著野馬向西逃了
All right, Margaret, keep us posted.
好吧 瑪格麗特 有消息及時告訴我們
We're on our way there.
我們正在趕過去
Give me an Indian whoop. Come on.
給我一個印第安式的歡呼 來吧
These boys gonna go down.
這些傢伙跑不了了
Let's get some giddy-up music going on there.
讓我們來點帶勁的音樂
Oh, please, not that.
啊 求你了 不要那個
Yeah.
好
Hey, hey. Come on. Snap out of it.
過來 別擋著
Snap the fuck out of it.
別擋著
Shit, let me see that. You're hit.
該死 讓我看看 你中槍了
Boy, you're hit. Get the back.
夥計 你中槍了 我看看後面
Well, you'll live. It's a through and through.
好 你會活下來的 子彈打穿了
Compress it. Wrap it up.
壓住它 包起來
You got to wrap it up tight.
你應該把它包緊
Front and back, front and back.
前後都要
Wrap it tight.
包緊
Oh, brother, hear me now, hear me clear.
兄弟 聽著 聽我說
Unless you wanna be a black mark on your sons' lives,
除非你想成為你兒子的黑色生命印記
I need you mountain lion mean.
我需要你振作起來
You hear me?
你聽到我的話了？
I hear you.
我聽到了
Mountain lion mean. Yeah.
振作起來
Yeah. It's gonna be okay, it's gonna be okay.
會好的 會好的
Hold on. Yeah.
堅持住
Go.
走
Here, take the money.
給你 拿著錢
Let's go. Get to the casino,
讓我們走 去賭場
change the money like we planned.
按照計畫換錢
This was your plan. And it worked.
這是你的計畫 而且的確有效
Every step of the way.
每一步都是
Trust it.
相信它
Where are you headed?
你要去哪裡？
Don't be stupid.
別做傻事
I love you, Toby.
我愛你 托比
I mean it.
我認真的
I love you, too.
我也愛你
Hey, tobe, go fuck yourself.
托比 去你的
Go fuck yourself.
去你的
Yippee hiyiyo. You little doggies.
你個小狗崽子
This is what they call white man's intuition.
這就是他們所說的 白人的直覺
Sometimes a blind pig finds a truffle.
有時候瞎貓也能碰到死耗子
Back up! Oh, shit!
後退！
Go! Move!
快！
My word.
天啊
All right. We're gonna need a SWAT unit up here
好吧 我們需要特警支援了
and a helo to pin these boys down.
還要直升機把那些傢伙弄下來
I'm on it.
我正在呼叫支援
Suspect is a white male.
疑犯是白人男性
He's got a rifle. Get down.
他有步槍 趴下
He's on the Ridge!
他在山脊上！
Come on! I see him!
我看到他了！
There's just one?
就一個？
Yep, just one.
是的 就一個
There's supposed to be two of them.
按說應該是兩個啊
Maybe the town folks got one.
也許在鎮上就抓住一個
Well, if they did, they got the smart one.
如果他們真抓到了一個 那他算是聰明的
This old boy is out of his mind.
這個孩子瘋了
Why don't you slip up this canyon
為什麼你不沖上山
tomahawk that son of a bitch?
劈了那個龜兒子呢？
Ranger down. Call it in.
警員中槍 通知他們
Get back. Back. Back those trucks up.
回去 回去
Get back.
回去
Get these trucks back.
這些卡車都回去
Back up.
支援
Back them up.
支援他們
How well you know the land around here?
你熟悉這裡的地形嗎？
Like the back of my hand.
瞭若指掌
All right. He's hid up in that brush on that hill.
好吧 他藏在那座山的樹叢後
Can you get me up there behind him?
你能帶我繞到他背後嗎？
Give me a half hour, I'll have that bastard
給我半個小時 我會逮住那個混蛋的
field dressed on the hood of my truck.
讓他躺在我的卡車上
I can't let you do that. You just get me there.
我不會讓你那麼做的 你只要帶我去那裡
That's gonna be a 500-yard shot if he's where you said.
如果他在你說的那個地方 那有500碼遠
Just get me there!
只要帶我去那裡！
Shit.
該死
How are you doing?
你好？
Good. You?
不錯 你呢？
Where are you headed?
要去哪裡？
Ruidoso.
魯伊多索鎮
Where you from?
你從哪裡來的？
Hamlin.
哈姆林
Taking the scenic route?
走風景線？
Taking the only way I can.
我只能走這條路
They got the road closed at post.
他們把波士特的路封了
Everywhere you turn they got the road closed.
每個路口都被封了
- You got your license on you? - Yes, I do.
- 帶駕照了嗎？- 是的 帶了
Wait right there.
等一下
Yes, sir.
是的 警官
- Sir. - Yeah.
- 先生 - 嗯？
Have a good day.
旅途愉快
Thanks much.
謝謝
You're pretty winded.
你喘的厲害
Y'ought a let me take the shot. Hell, it's my gun.
你應該讓我射 見鬼 這是我的槍
Not on your life. He's mine.
這不是你該做的 他是我的
Just left of the tree.
就在樹的左邊
I got him.
逮到他了
I got you.
抓到你了
Lord of the plains.
神的平原
That's me.
那是我
Texas highway patrol and the locals
德州高速巡邏隊和當地居民一起
chased the robbers to this hillside behind me,
在我身後的山邊追擊劫匪
20 miles west of town, where the gunfight continued.
就在鎮子以西20英里 繼續槍戰
And right now we do know
現在我們所知
ranger Marcus Hamilton killed one of the gunmen
遊騎兵馬庫斯漢密爾頓 擊斃了其中一個
using a rifle he actually borrowed from a resident here.
使用的步槍是從當地居民借來的
We don't know the name of that suspect yet...
我們暫時還不知道嫌犯的名字
Lucky guy.
幸運的傢伙
Just in the Nick of time, too.
時間正好
What are the odds?
很少出現這種情況
Now, this, uh, satisfies
現在 這個 滿足了
both the reverse mortgage loan and the, uh...
抵押貸款和……
And the back taxes that we've paid on your mother's behalf.
和我們替你媽媽支付的稅款
We do that as courtesy, of course.
我們那麼做是出於好心 當然
You can fax the release of lien to that number.
你可以把檔傳真到那個號碼
An attorney?
律師？
All right. Well, I'll...
好吧 好 我將……
I'll get that faxed over to your attorney by the end of the week.
我週末之前會傳真給你的律師
It is the end of the week. I wanna watch you do it.
今天是週末 我要看著你傳完
Well, it takes a little time to prepare.
好吧 需要一點時間準備
I got all day.
我今天整天都有空
Okay. That's it.
好的 可以了
And it's been a pleasure doing business with you.
很高興和你做生意
Let me ask you a question.
讓我問你一個問題
Do y'all manage trusts?
你們管理信託嗎？
Hey, Marcus, ain't you supposed to be retired?
馬庫斯 你不是該退休了嗎？
Howdy.
你好
Nice to see you.
很高興見到你
Well, hey, Marcus.
嗨 馬庫斯
Hey, Margaret.
嗨 瑪格麗特
Been awhile. How's life as a civilian?
有一陣子沒見了 平民生活還好嗎？
Oh, just, you know...
哦 你知道……
Think I can take a peek at Mr. Howard's file?
我能看一眼霍華德的檔案嗎？
Tanner Howard.
泰納 霍華德
Oh, come on. I ain't got nothing better to do.
少來 我不是沒事可做
It's at my desk.
在我的桌子上
He killed this father in a hunting accident, huh?
他在一次打獵事故中 殺了他的父親？
I'd love to know what he was hunting in the barn in April.
據我所知 是4月份在穀倉裡的打獵
Ten years in huntsville for aggravated assault.
在漢茨維爾監獄關了10年 因為惡意謀殺
Cellmate was released in 2012.
他的獄友在2012年被釋放
Before that, he served seven years
服刑7年
on bank robbery charges up in big spring.
因為搶劫銀行
Been trying to track him down, but no luck so far.
所以出來學著搶銀行 但是沒有那麼走運
You all are off the brother?
你們調查過他的兄弟嗎？
There's nothing that links him to the robberies.
沒有證據能聯繫到他兄弟
And what about that little waitress in Vernon?
維農女招待的證詞呢？
Yeah, we showed her photos,and she said she didn't recognize him.
我們給她看過照片 她沒有認出來他
Pretty upset you took her tips as evidence.
她很氣憤你拿走了她的小費當證據
She sure was sassy.
她是很蠻橫
You show that to that old timer?
你給她看的是這張老照片？
Yup. She said he didn't look like the fella from the diner.
她說看起來不像用餐的那個傢伙
She didn't recognize Tanner's photo either.
她也沒有認出泰納的照片
Yeah. Tried to get a court order
我們還試著申請法庭命令
on his bank accounts and the ranch,
調查他的帳戶和農場
DA wouldn't do it. Toby's got no record.
檢察官不願意那麼做 托比沒有犯罪記錄
He's never been arrested.
從來沒有被逮捕過
His only court appearance was at his divorce.
唯一的出庭記錄是離婚
He don't fit the bill, Marcus.
他不符合要求 馬庫斯
People don't start out robbing banks.
人們不相信他會搶銀行
They graduate to it like his asshole brother.
都認為是他的混蛋哥哥幹的
Besides, when we was out there,
此外 我們到那裡的時候
we saw two crews from chevron
我們看到兩組雪佛龍公司來的人
capping Wells and putting in pumpjacks.
正在安裝鑽井架
Engineers out there said they're gonna pull
工程師說他們那裡有石油
2, 000 barrels a month off that place.
每個月至少2000桶
You just try convincing a judge
你需要說服法官
to issue warrants on somebody
給一個月收入5萬元的傢伙開搜查證
set to clear $50,000 a month for robbing $40,000 from the bank
罪名是從銀行了搶了4萬元
that manages the family trust.
而且那家銀行還管理著他們家的信託
Midlands manages the trust?
米德蘭茲銀行管理著他家的信託？
You'd think they'd want this thing figured out.
你覺得他們想要案情水落石出
I don't think the bank cares about anything
我不認為銀行還關心這個
but keeping that trust right where it is.
他們更關心能否留住那個信託
Hell, they were less cooperative than Toby's attorney.
他們主要通過托比的律師合作
Marcus, he's not a suspect and you are retired.
馬庫斯 他不是嫌疑犯 你也該退休了
Oh, I hear you.
我聽到了
You like the desk?
你喜歡這桌子？
I don't hate it.
我不恨它
Hey, I'll see you, Marcus.
我會去看你的 馬庫斯
Know who I am?
知道我是誰嗎？
I'm the man who killed your brother.
我是殺死你哥哥的人
I know.
我知道
I also know you're retired and you're trespassing.
我還知道你退休了 並且你侵犯了私人領地
Oh, you could shoot me now
你現在可以射我
and be within your rights.
那是你的權力
You toting a gun and all, how convenient.
你拿著槍 非常方便
I figure you got one, too.
我覺得你肯定也帶著槍
Mind if I sit?
我能坐坐嗎？
Go ahead.
來吧
You want a beer?
要啤酒嗎？
Sure. I ain't on duty no more.
當然 我現在不當差了
Thanks.
謝謝
It's nice out here in this breeze, though,
出來透透氣很好
now that it's cooled down.
現在涼快下來了
How did you do it?
你怎麼做到的？
Oh, never mind.I'll figure that out in time.
別介意 我會想明白的
Why? Why did you do it?
為什麼？為什麼你要做那個？
I know why your brother, Tanner, did it.
我知道你哥哥泰納為什麼那麼做
He robbed them banks because he liked it.
他搶銀行因為他喜歡那麼做
He shot my partner 300 yards away
他在300碼外射中了我的搭檔
because he liked it, it made him feel good.
因為他喜歡 那讓他感覺不錯
If I hadn't blown his shit for brains out,
如果我沒有轟出他的腦漿
there'd be a new truck out front with jet skis,
估計前面會停著一輛新卡車
and whatever else he could think to buy.
不然他還會買什麼
He'd spend it all just to give him
他會花光所有的錢
an excuse to steal some more.
只是為了給他一個偷更多東西的藉口
But not you.
但是你不一樣
There's nothing new around here,
這裡並沒有添置新東西
except them pumpjacks.
除了他們的抽油機
Each one of them making you a month
每個月賺的錢
what you and your brother stole
都比你和你哥哥從那四家銀行
from all four banks combined.
偷的錢多
Help me understand, then.
幫我解開這個謎團
Help me understand why four people died
讓我明白為什麼四個人死了
so you could steal money that it don't seem you've spent,
你偷了錢 但是並沒有花掉
that it don't seem you need.
似乎你也不缺錢
You got a family?
你有家庭嗎？
My partner had a family. A big one.
我的搭檔有家庭 很大一家子
They don't got no pumpjacks in their backyard.
不過他們的後院 沒有抽油機
I didn't kill your friend.
我沒有殺死你的朋友
Yes, you did.
是的 你幹了
By setting this thing in motion.
通過計畫具體的行動
You expect me to believe your dimwitted brother planned this?
你想讓我相信 都是你那笨哥哥設計的嗎？
Oh, no. This was smart, this was you.
不 這一切都太聰明了 是你設計的
I've been poor my whole life.
我一輩子都很窮
So were my parents, their parents before them.
我的父母也一樣 他們的父母也一樣
It's like a disease
就像是疾病
passing from generation to generation,
一代一代的遺傳下來
becomes a sickness, that's what it is.
變成了頑疾
Infects every person you know,
傳染給你認識的每一個人
but not my boys.
但是我的兒子不再是了
Not anymore.
不再是了
This is theirs now.
這裡是他們的了
Now, I ain't never killed no one in my life,
現在 我絕不會再殺人了
but if you want me to start with you,
但如果你想讓我開始殺戮
let's get on with it, old man.
試試看吧 老傢伙
See if you can grab that pistol
看看你能否順利地掏出槍
before I blast you off this porch.
在我把你從走廊轟下去之前
Howdy. What's going on?
你好 怎麼了？
The hogs are back in the garden.
豬圈在後園裡
Feral hogs tearing up this place something fierce.
野豬把這裡拱得一塌糊塗
Who's this?
這是誰？
I'm an old friend of your husband.
我是你丈夫的老朋友
Ex-husband.
前夫
I'm just working on the house.
我只是來收拾一下房子
Oh, you don't live here?
你不住在這裡？
No, it's not mine. It's theirs.
不 這不是我的 是他們的
The things we do for our kids, huh?
我們做的一切都是為了孩子 對嗎？
Well...
好…
I best be going.
我得走了
Ma'am.
夫人
Me too, Debbie. I'm gonna wash up,
我也得走了 黛比 我得去洗一洗了
be back around 9:00 tomorrow to finish the front.
我明天早上9點回來 把前面的活幹完
Start painting the extension,
開始粉刷外牆
and then help Randy with his homework
然後幫蘭迪做作業
when he gets back from school, okay?
在他放學後 好嗎？
Okay.
好吧
I'm renting a little house in town.
我在鎮上租了一間小房子
If you wanna stop by and finish this conversation,
如果你路過的時候想繼續聊聊
you're welcome anytime.
隨時歡迎你
Oh, I'd like that.
哦 我喜歡那樣
I'll be seeing you.
我會去看著你的
Yeah. Soon, I hope.
是的 快了 我希望
I'm ready to be done with this.
我已經準備好結束這些了
You'll never be done with it no matter what.
無論如何 你絕對不能再做了
It's gonna haunt you, son, for the rest of your days.
它會追著你的 在你的餘生
But you won't be alone. It's gonna haunt me, too.
但是你不會孤獨 它也會追著我的
If you stop by, maybe I'll give you peace.
如果你停手 也許我會給你和平
Maybe. Maybe I'll give it to you.
也許 也許我會給你的